Guide to the Radovic Collection of Pittsburgh Theatre Programs, 1927-1931 CTC.1962.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Radovic Collection of Pittsburgh Theatre Programs
1927-1931
CTC.1962.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
1.5 linear feet (3 boxes, 28 folders)
This collection contains a nearly complete record of the George Sharp Players, a Pittsburgh stock company, as well as additional materials on other Pittsburgh stock companies compiled by John M. Radovic and his sister Dorothy.
Radovic, John M.
History
This collection of Pittsburgh theatre programs and related clippings was compiled almost entirely by John M. Radovic, who attended Pittsburgh theatre regularly from 1916 until his untimely death in 1931 at age 31. The collection is of particular interest because it represents an almost complete record of the George Sharp Players, by far the best and most durable of Pittsburgh's stock companies.
The George Sharp Players enjoyed five consecutive seasons in Pittsburgh from 1927 to 1931, offering the typical stock company bill -- melodrama, light comedy, mystery, and farce. Among performers who went on to national stardom are Paul McGrath, Alexander Kirkland, Ralph Morgan, Anne Forrest, and Ann Harding. Leading lady Ann Harding, with her husband, Harry Bannister, broke away in 1928 to form a rival company, the Nixon Players, taking their name from the theatre in which they played; the company lasted only one season. The George Sharp Players performed at the Pitt Shubert until their final month in 1931 at the Pitt Alvin. Similar to other stock companies throughout the country, the George Sharp Players were forced to close because of the increasing popularity of motion pictures.
George Sharp returned to Pittsburgh for a brief season late in 1932, to manage the Edwin Vail Players, which then changed its name to the George Sharp Players. In 1934 he came again, to stage a few plays at the Fort Pitt Hotel. He died in Los Angeles in 1951.
Scope and Content Notes
The collection is comprised mainly of programs and clippings, and is divided into two series. Series I contains the bulk of the collection including programs and clippings relating to the George Sharp Players. Series II holds programs and clippings for the Nixon Players and various stock companies in Pittsburgh theatres.
Arrangement
Series I. George Sharp Players
Series II. Various Stock Companies in Pittsburgh Theatres
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Dorothy B. Radovic in 1962.
Previous Citation
Radovic Collection of Pittsburgh Theatre Programs, 1927-1931, CTC.1962.01, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Radovic Collection of Pittsburgh Theatre Programs, 1927-1931, CTC.09, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Related Material
Pitt Theatre materials, Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of Pittsburgh Theatre Programs, 1840-present, CTC.1966.01, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Fort Pitt Hotel, Curtis Pittsburgh Performing Arts Information Files
Edwin Vail Players (Theater company).; George Sharp Players (Theater company).; Nixon Players (Theater company).; Radovic, Dorothy B.; Radovic, John M.; Sharp, George; Alvin Theatre (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Comedy; Davis Theatre (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Duquesne Theatre (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Farce; Gayety Theatre (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Heinz House (Pittsburgh, Pa.).; Lyceum Theatre (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Melodrama; Mystery; Nixon Theatre (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Performing arts -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Theater; Theater -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh
- George Sharp Players, I.
  Scope and Contents note
  Series I contains the bulk of the collection including programs and clippings relating to the George Sharp Players. Sharp Points is a small weekly circular that advertised the George Sharp Players' current and future performances. The newspaper clippings are undated, but are contemporary to the programs and other Sharp materials. The reviews are clipped from newspapers and are also undated. They are arranged alphabetically by title of production.
  - Programs, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1928 (Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1929 (Folder 3)
  - Programs, 1930 (Folder 4-5)
  - Programs, 1931 (Folder 6)
  - Sharp Points, 1928 (Folder 7)
  - Clippings, General (Folder 8)
  - Clippings, Pictures (Folder 9)
  - Clippings, Anne Forrest (Folder 10)
  - Clippings, Ads (Folder 11)
  - Reviews, A-Z (Box 2, Folder 1-8)
- Various Stock Companies in Pittsburgh Theatres, II.
  - Programs, Nixon Players, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, Nixon Players (Folder 2)
  - Reviews, Nixon Players (Folder 3)
  - Clippings, Ann Harding, Harry Bannister (Folder 4)
  - Clippings, "Showstops" Columns by Karl Krug on Pittsburgh Stock Theatre (Folder 5)
  - Clippings, Pittsburgh Stock Companies (Folder 6-8)